开始
Go!
拉杰  加油
Come on, Raj!
你可以的
You can do this!
绝对不可能
There's no way.
这是在干嘛
What is happening?
这是欧拉盘
This is an Euler's Disk.
是一种物理学玩具
It's a physics toy
用来演示角动量
that demonstrates angular momentum,
势能与动能
potential energy, and kinetic energy.
你们几个小宅男还看体育呢
Aw, look at you watching sports.
我们在打赌库萨帕里
We're betting to see if Koothrappali
能不能憋气到这欧拉盘静止后才呼吸
can hold his breath longer than the disk can spin.
它的重量与平滑度
Its weight and smoothness,
再加上底下镜面盘的些微凹度
along with the slight concavity of the mirror,
都意味着它可以转很久
means it can spin for a long time.
但拉杰来自印度
But Raj is from India,
这表示在憋气这件事上  他也是经验丰富
which means he's no slouch at holding his breath.
我也要赌  我赌十块钱
Okay, I want in. Ten bucks says
我会在这玩意静止之前就对这事失去兴致
I'll lose interest before that thing stops spinning.
谢尔顿  我找到一家适合约会的餐厅
Hey, Sheldon, I found a great restaurant for date night.
现在很忙  别吵
Kind of busy right now.
是欧拉盘  真有趣
Oh, an Euler's Disk! Fun!
我们在看是它转的时间久  还是拉杰憋气时间久
Yeah, we're seeing if Raj can hold his breath longer than it.
真幼稚
Oh. Immature.
憋得住吗
How ya doing?
他绝对不行
He's not gonna make it.
-他行的  -你知道吗
- Yes, he is! - You know,
深水潜水员在憋气好几分钟后
deep-sea divers holding their breath for several minutes
所发出脑损伤信号的
have shown elevated markers of a protein
蛋白质明显增多
that can signal brain damage.
这里正发生的事情也是脑损伤的信号
Yeah, see, what's happening here signals brain damage.
天啊  这东西会转多久啊
My God, how long does this thing spin for?
你感兴趣了  十块钱输掉啦
Ha! You're interested! You're out ten bucks!
-开始慢下来了  -发挥你的潜力
- It's slowing down! - Dig deep!
就像那次我们打赌你穿不进霍华德的裤子
Like when we bet you couldn't fit into Howard's pants!
他撑不下去啦
He's not gonna make it!
他可以的
Yes, he is!
加油啊  拉杰  就像你最爱的电影
Come on, Raj! It's like your favorite movie!
你要"憋到梦醒时分"
You're just Waiting to Exhale!
我就知道你可以
Yeah! I knew you could do it!
另...  另外告诉你
And j.. and just so you know,
我最爱的电影...
my favorite movie...
是《公主新娘》
is Princess Bride.
拉杰什  最近好吗
Hello, Rajesh. How are things by you?
挺好  挺好啊
Good, good.
我想先跟你说一下
Uh, listen, I just wanted to let you know
你这个月看到我信用卡账单时
when you get my credit card bill,
可能会发现这个月账有点多
it might be a little high this month.
毕竟你也是个有稳定工作收入的成年人
Well, you're a grown man with a steady job.
花光你老爸的钱也是合情合理的嘛
Why wouldn't you spend all your father's money?
爹爹  你真是又有钱又幽默
Oh, Daddy, you're so rich and funny.
所以你最近还有什么别的事呢
Yeah. So what else is going on with your life?
我之前跟大学里的一个女人约会
Uh, well, I was dating a woman at the university,
不过后来分手了
but we broke up.
我很遗憾听到这消息
I'm sorry to hear that.
我知道  以我帮你买了新iPad来安慰我
I know you are. That's why you just bought me a new iPad.
我想先告诉你
And before you start,
我对你的包办婚姻一点兴趣都没有
I am not interested in you arranging a marriage for me.
我几百年前就放弃这事了好吗
Oh, I gave up on that a long time ago.
是吗
You did?
太累人了
It's too much work.
你都几岁了还得靠
You're an adult who can't get by
老爸老妈给的零花钱才能过活
without an allowance from his parents.
女人才不喜欢这种男人
Women don't want that.
你啥意思啊  你放弃我了吗
Wh-What are you saying, that y-you're giving up on me?
什么样的爸爸会放弃自己的儿子啊
What kind of father gives up on his son?
我有六个孩子
I have six children,
其中五个都已婚  而且能养活自己
five of whom are married and self-sufficient.
我想问题应该不在我身上
I don't think I'm the problem.
真不敢相信你会说这种话
I can't believe what I'm hearing.
太伤人家的小心肝了
This is deeply hurtful.
你还是个玻璃心
You're also too sensitive.
女人也不喜欢这种男人
Women don't want that either.
这里的餐点据说很好吃
The food here's supposed to be great.
别洋芋片吃饱了
Don't fill up on chips.
不会的  我有个小秘诀
Oh, I won't. I have a trick.
我只吃等边三角形的洋芋片
I only eat equilateral triangles.
等腰  等腰三角形
Isosceles, isosceles,
不等边三角形...
oh, scalene...
你没看到这幕
You didn't see that.
你看是伯特  在吧台那里
Oh, look. It's Bert, at the bar.
我们应该过去打个招呼
We should go say hi.
为什么
Why?
因为这是正常人
Because that's what you do
在公共场合看到认识的人时该做的举动
when you see someone you know in a public place.
我有好几张限制令证明不是这样
I have multiple restraining orders that say otherwise.
谢尔顿  跟朋友打个招呼与
Sheldon, there's a difference between greeting a friend
跟踪名人进厕所是有区别的
and following a celebrity into a bathroom.
连法官都不能跟我解释通
If the judge couldn't explain it to me,
你凭什么觉得你行呢
I don't see how you will.
-伯特  -你好
- Hi, Bert. - Hello.
你们好呀
Oh, hey, guys.
你们怎么会在这里
What brings you here?
-我们是来约会的  -不错嘛
- Oh, we're having date night. - Nice.
我也约了人
I'm meeting someone, too.
是吗  是我们认识的人吗
Oh, really. Anybody we know?
应该不是  我们是在天地合网上认识的
I doubt it. I met her on G-Harmony.
那是专门为地质学家创立的婚恋网站
That's a Web site for geologists to find love.
还真有这种网站啊
That's a real thing?
当然  他们的口号是"合时为你安排约会
Yeah. Their slogan is "we're all about dating
而非用碳14测何时"
and not the carbon-14 kind."
祝你们有个美好的夜晚
Well, have a lovely evening.
谢谢  你们也一样
Thanks. You, too.
如果你觉得这样比跟明星扎克瑞·昆图
If you think that's more fun than talking to Zachary Quinto
隔着厕所门说话更有意思  那你真是疯了
through a stall door, you're crazy.
其实我们可以去你们家
You know, we could've come to you guys.
这样就不用把宝宝带过来了啦
You didn't have to bring the baby here.
没关系  走出家门的感觉真好
Oh, it's okay. It's good to get out of the house.
而且她一坐车就乖乖睡觉
And the car ride puts her to sleep.
以前这招对谢尔顿也管用
Aw, that used to work with Sheldon.
是啊  直到某人把他扔在药店的停车场
Yeah, until someone left him in the drugstore parking lot
让他吓了个半死
and he freaked out.
是谁忘了把车窗留一点缝
Who forgot to crack the window?
你们好呀
Hello!
有人去古奇购物了
Someone's been shopping at Gucci.
是啊  我觉得超适合哈雷就忍不住买了
Yeah, I saw something for Halley and I couldn't resist.
你真是太好了
That's so sweet of you.
是压皱天鹅绒宝宝斗篷哦
Yeah, it's a crushed velvet baby cape.
不是吧  现在我们有两件了
Oh, no, now we have two.
-一定很贵吧  -是啊
- That must've been expensive. - Yeah, it was.
但花的是我老爹的钱  反正我也不爽他
But it's my father's money and I'm mad at him.
你跟你爸怎么了
What's going on with your dad?
如果你真的想惹毛他
And if you really want to hurt him,
我穿香奈儿可好看了
I look great in Chanel.
我才发现他根本不在乎我结婚还是单身
It turns out he doesn't care if I'm married or if I'm single.
他基本已经放弃我了
He's basically given up on me.
我敢说一定不是真的
Oh, I'm sure that's not true.
是真的  他不再帮我找印度姑娘逼我成亲了
It is. He stopped trying to find Indian girls for me to marry.
你爸这么做时  你也只是一昧抱怨啊
All you did was complain when he did that.
莱纳德  他正伤心呢  让他发泄
Leonard, he's hurting. Let him feel how he feels.
-多谢体谅  佩妮  -不客气
- Thank you, Penny. - Yeah.
我鞋子穿7码半  靴子穿8码
Shoes, I'm a seven-and-a-half; boots, I'm an eight.
MSN搜索
...MSN Search,
阿尔塔维斯塔
AltaVista,
有事就问吉福斯
and... Ask Jeeves.
你呢
You?
抱歉  我没有需要怀念的过气搜索引擎列表
Sorry, I don't have a list of defunct search engines that I miss.
看来我被人放鸽子了
Hey. Looks like I got stood up,
-所以我还是走吧  -别啊
- so I'm gonna head out. - Oh, no.
你确定不再多等她几分钟吗
Are you sure you don't want to give her a few more minutes?
不了  天地合网的建议等待时间是两小时
Nah, G-Harmony recommends after two hours,
是时候该放弃了
it's time to cut bait.
我感到很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
伯特  请你加入我们吧
Bert, I insist that you join us.
你真的不介意吗
You really wouldn't mind?
完全不会  艾米你呢
Not at all. Amy?
我也不介意
Fine with me.
谢谢  那我去拿把椅子
Thanks. I'll go grab a chair.
谢尔顿  你的举动真是太暖了
Sheldon, that was so sweet of you.
我从他的脸部表情和肢体语言
Well, I could deduce by his facial expression
推断出他很难过
and body language that he was sad.
他说自己被人放鸽子时没有给你点提示吗
So the part where he got stood up didn't clue you in?
你还指望我会一边观察他  一边听他的废话吗
You want me to look at him and listen to him?
我父亲觉得我的每段感情之所以不成功
My father thinks the reason I can't make a relationship work
是因为我是被宠坏的屁孩
is because I'm spoiled.
抱歉  他是在等着有人提出反对意见吗
I'm sorry, is he waiting for someone to disagree?
就因为他帮我解决问题
Just because he helps me out
并不意味着我被他宠坏了
doesn't automatically mean that I'm spoiled.
好吧  那他到底帮你解决多少账单
All right, how much exactly does he pay for?
我会告诉你们
Okay, I'll tell you,
但请不要鄙视我
but please don't judge me.
我的车  我的房租和信用卡的账单都是他付的
He pays for my car, my rent, and my credit cards.
我在努力忍住  但我已经鄙视你了
I'm trying, but I'm judging.
或许你爸说得对
Maybe your dad's right.
对啊  女人的确喜欢能养活自己的男人
Yeah, women do like a man that can support himself.
但伯纳黛特挣的钱比霍华德多
But Bernadette makes more money than Howard.
基本是她在养活自己老公啊
She basically supports him.
是啊  或许你爸是对的
Yeah, maybe your dad's right.
好问题  我想想
Good question. Let's see.
搜信
Infoseek,
网络蜘蛛
WebCrawler,
热机器人
oh, HotBot.
够了  真的换个什么话题都行
Okay, literally any other topic.
好吧  你们俩是怎么认识的
All right. How did you guys meet?
其实我们是在网上认识的
Actually, we met online.
我们第一次约会是在一家咖啡馆
Our-our first date was at a coffee shop.
不过跟你的约会对象不一样  她可是真来了
Although, unlike your date, she actually showed up.
他又看起来难过了
Oh, he looks sad again.
我真的很羡慕你们的感情
Well, I really envy your relationship.
除了你们俩一年只做一次爱这点
Other than you two only having sex once a year,
你们简直是完美情侣档
you're the perfect couple.
你知道这件事吗
You-you know about that?
整个大学谁不知道呀
Uh, yeah, everyone at the university does.
你知道这件事吗
Were you aware of this?
不  这事我只告诉过莱纳德  霍华德  拉杰
No. No, I only told Leonard, Howard, Raj,
克里普克  吴教授  克莱因教授
Kripke, uh, Professor Wu, Professor Klein,
还有一个食堂大妈
and a lunch lady in the cafeteria.
我也想不通其他人是怎么知道的
How everyone else found out is a mystery to me.
你为什么不理我了
Why aren't you talking to me?
因为我对你很生气
Because I'm mad at you.
现在我后悔问了这个问题
Well, now I'm sorry I asked.
谢尔顿  我的脸都丢完了
Sheldon, it's humiliating.
因为你  我的同事们都在八卦我们的性生活
Thanks to you, my colleagues are gossiping about our sex life.
这有什么可八卦的呀
What is there to gossip about?
我们都没做过几次
We barely have one.
所以他们才感兴趣呀
That's why they're doing it!
我可以理解为你再也不想和我说话了吗
Is it safe to assume you're not speaking to me again?
如果你是因为不想理我所以不回答
If you're not answering because you're not speaking to me,
也许我们可以用某种信号来表示
perhaps we could come up with a signal!
我懂了
That works!
你才不需要你爸的钱
You don't need your dad's money.
-你的收入足够养活你自己了  -没错
- You can get by on your salary. - Yeah.
我们和你一样都在学校工作
Well, we work at the same place as you, and
-我们就活得挺好  -得了吧
- we've always been fine. - Oh, please.
拜托照照镜子  你俩看起来比我老十岁
Look in the mirror. You both look ten years older than I do.
好吧
All right.
等等  我们一定有办法解决的
Hang on. We can figure this out.
我们先清理一下你的开销  你每月房租多少
Let's just go over your expenses. How much is your rent?
我不想回答
I don't want to say.
高到特别离谱吗
Is it really that high?
我不想回答因为我不知道多少钱
I don't want to say because I don't know how much it is.
你连自己的房租都不知道吗
You don't how much your rent is?
我爸帮我付房租啦  你知道你的房租多少钱吗
My father pays for it! Do you know how much your rent is?!
当然知道
Yeah.
那就按你房租的两倍算吧
Well, then double it,
我的房子比你这垃圾堆舒服多了
because my building's a lot nicer than this dump.
那你知道每个月养车要多少钱吗
Do you know how much your car costs?
不知道
Not really.
每个月吃饭要多少钱
Well, how much do you spend on food?
吃的全是家政工负责买好
The housekeeper does the shopping.
我的乖乖  你真是被宠坏了
Oh, my God, you really are spoiled.
我被宠坏了
I'm spoiled?!
你闺女一件披风都价值300美金好嘛
Your baby has a cape that costs $300!
我要睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
等一下
Well, wait.
这是我们同居之后第一次吵架
This is our first fight as a couple who live together.
所以呢
So?
我对这种事的规矩还不太懂
I'm not sure of the protocol.
电视里教的是
Television teaches us
这种情况下男的应该去睡沙发
that the man's supposed to sleep on the couch,
但我们当中明显是你的体型更适合睡沙发
but of the two of us, you're clearly more sofa-sized.
我才不会为了
I'm not sleeping on the couch
你不懂什么叫私事而滚去睡沙发
'cause you don't know what's private and what's not.
这不公平
This isn't fair.
你还不是和佩妮
You've discussed aspects
讨论过我俩的肉体关系
of our physical relationship with Penny.
那不一样
That's different!
她是我的闺蜜  不是你那位
She's a close friend, not the lady in the cafeteria
帮三明治去面包皮的食堂大妈
who cuts the crust off your sandwiches!
人家大妈也是有名字的
That lady has a name.
虽然我不知道她的芳名
I don't know what it is,
但有一次  我不小心喊了她一声妈
but one time, I accidentally called her mom?
看来你得先搬去便宜的地方住了
Sounds like you're gonna need a cheaper place to live.
你刚来这里时也没多少钱
When you moved here, you didn't have a lot of money.
你是怎么过下来的
How'd you get by?
有时候你可以从邻居那里蹭到
Well, sometimes you can get free food
免费的食物和网络
and Wi-Fi from the neighbors.
只不过
Just know
最后你可能得嫁给其中的一个人
you might have to marry one of 'em.
对了  斯图尔特都住在你们家了
Hey, you guys let Stuart live with you.
不如也让拉杰一起住吧
Why not Raj, too?
你这是在干嘛呀  我...
What-what are you doing? I...
我拖着孩子来你家聚会  还带了进口啤酒
I-I-I schlepped the baby over, I brought imported beer.
你为什么还不喜欢我
Why don't you like me?
拜托  我以为我俩是好朋友呢
Well, I thought we were best friends!
我们是呀
We are!
一想到好朋友将要无家可归  我真伤心难过
That's why I'm sad my best friend's gonna be homeless.
抱歉  拉杰  我们家真的没地方了
I'm sorry, Raj. We really just don't have the space.
不如让他住你家车库吧
What if he lives in your garage?
不如你丫赶紧闭嘴吧
What if you stop helping?!
各位  我才不要住车库呢
Guys, I'm not living in a garage!
等等  干嘛总纠结我的房子呢
Wait. Why are we talking about our place
谢尔顿的房间明明还空着呀
when Sheldon's old room is sitting there perfectly empty?
这个主意不错
That's a great idea.
拉杰  如果你需要地方住
Raj, if you need a place to stay,
我们家永远为你敞开
of course you are welcome here.
谢了  但如果我要给朋友添麻烦的话
Thank you, but if I'm gonna just take advantage of my friends,
我还不如继续靠我爹养着呢
I might as well keep on relying on my father.
好吧  你决定了就好
Okay, only if you're sure.
好险
Whew.
万幸
Yeah.
艾米
Amy?
-艾米  -干嘛
- Amy? - Yeah?
虽然你口气不善  但也行吧
Not exactly the welcome wagon, but I'll take it.
这是什么
What is this?
我画了一张图  列出了和谁
I'm mapping basic topics of conversation
应该讨论什么样的话题
and with whom they can be discussed.
我管这些圆圈叫"隐私地带"
I call these circles Zones of Privacy.
别搜索这个词
Don't Google that
除非你想看人类性器官的图片
unless you want to see pictures of people's genitals.
这个圈里只有我和你
This circle contains only me and you.
代表我们只跟对方分享的话题
It represents subjects we only share with each other--
身体亲密行为的细节  如厕习惯
details of physical intimacy, bathroom habits.
不过说着说着
Although, as I'm saying it,
我觉得有必要加上芬克医生
I may need to add Dr. Fink in here.
你真的担心
Are you really worried
向史蒂芬·霍金透露秘密吗
about revealing secrets to Stephen Hawking?
不  我只是很兴奋能将他列为好友
No, I was just excited to list him as a friend.
谢谢你为我做这些
Well, I do appreciate you working on this.
对不起我让你觉得丢脸了
I'm sorry you were embarrassed.
现在我懂了
And now I understand that
有些事只能你知我知
some things are just between you and me,
万一有红肿和肿胀  芬克医生也要知
and in the event of redness and swelling, Dr. Fink.
中间那个小点是什么
What's that little dot in the middle?
那是我不与任何人分享的想法
That's reserved for thoughts I don't share with anyone.
有意思
Interesting.
你真有没告诉我的秘密吗
You really have secrets you don't tell me?
当然有
Of course.
可以说一个听听吗
Can I hear one?
不行  这是隐私
No, they're private.
为什么  是很"不乖"的吗
Why? Are they naughty?
一点点吧
A little.
求你了
Please?
好
Fine.
两年前...
Two years ago...
我拿到了驾照
...I got my driver's license.
什么
What?!
你为什么没说
Why didn't you say anything?!
我喜欢有司机接送
I like being chauffeured around.
这让我觉得自己是大人物
It makes me feel important.
我清晨四点起来  送你穿越沙漠
So when I got up at 4:00 A.M. to drive you across the desert
去古董火车博物馆  其实不必我去吗
to an antique train museum, I didn't have to?
是  你不必
No, you didn't.
但你记得
But keep in mind,
那让我觉得自己是超级大人物
I felt extremely important.
什么事
What?!
你好  父亲
Hello, Father.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
好的
All right.
我做出了重要决定
I have come to an important decision.
我不会再拿你的钱
I will not be accepting your money anymore.
我是个男人  可以照顾好自己
I'm a man, and I can take care of myself.
太好了
That's wonderful!
是的 非常好
Yes, that is wonderful!
你不能再指责我被宠坏了
You will no longer be able to accuse me of being spoiled!
我真为你骄傲
I am so proud of you.
爸  我是想臭骂你一顿
Dad, I'm trying to tell you off,
你的欣喜与宽慰毁了我的计划
and you're ruining it with your delight and relief.
抱歉
Sorry.
不要啊  我已成年的儿子不想再花光我的钱了
Oh, no, my grown son is going to stop spending all my money.
我这个当爹的是哪里做得不对啊
Where did I fail as a father?!
这就对了
Yeah, that's right.
好好问问你自己这个问题
Keep asking yourself that!
但我依然非常爱你  所以别把我踢出遗嘱
But I still love you very much, so don't cut me out of the will.
你自己做了午餐
Oh, you brought your own lunch.
好样的
Good for you.
我在做出很多改变
Yeah, I'm making a bunch of changes.
今天早上  我辞退了遛狗人
This morning, I fired my dog walker.
那狗怎么上厕所
Oh. How's the dog gonna go to the bathroom?
我让她吃了止泻药
Uh, I gave her an Imodium.
这是明天的问题了
That's tomorrow's problem.
不好意思  大家注意下好吗
Excuse me. May I have your attention, please?
我最近意识到
I have recently been made aware
我与艾米·菲拉·福勒的私人关系
that my personal relationship with Amy Farrah Fowler
成为了饮水机旁的八卦谈资
has become water cooler gossip.
我只想说  你们真可耻
And I just want to say, shame on all of you.
我们是科学家
We're scientists.
我们应该集中精神
Our minds should be focused
关注人类知识的进步
on the advancement of human knowledge,
而不是其他人的私生活细节
not the intimate details of other people's lives.
他说得对
He's right.
抱歉我在这件事中扮演的角色
And I'm sorry for the part I played in this.
谢谢你  伯特
Thank you, Bert.
你是个好人  昨天放你鸽子
You're a good man. That woman who stood you up
令你蒙羞的女人  真是走宝了
and humiliated you last night really missed out.
这样说可建立不了我的光辉形象
That doesn't paint me in the best light.
这样啊  对不起
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
纠正  那个女人不仅和伯特床战三百回合
Correction: That woman not only had vigorous coitus with Bert...
而且还因为他活儿好  给了一块钱小费
she also tipped him a dollar for a job well done.
-光辉起来了吗  -没有
- That better? - Not really.
好了  总之  专注于科学
All right, well, to sum up-- focus on science,
别管别人的事
keep your nose out of other people's business,
还有  想寻欢作乐  就找伯特
and, uh, whoa, for a good time, call Bert.
这是唱的哪一出
What brought that on?
昨晚艾米生气了
Well, last night Amy was angry with me
因为我傻里傻气地告诉别人
because I'd been foolishly telling people
某些隐私事情
about certain personal matters.
生气是正常的
That's understandable.
我现在知道了
Oh, I know that now.
起初  我以为她脾气暴躁
At first, I thought she was cranky
是因为她很严重的经痛  但是
because of her horrific menstrual cramps, but...
结果不是  她只是真的觉得丢人
...it turns out, no, she was genuinely mortified.